ID	Section	Check	Detail	Tags	Status	Details	Details	Details	Details	Details	Details
0.1	00 Before you start	App starts and reaches the login page	Expect: no unhandled exception in the console. A SqlException here means the connection string is wrong — fix that before anything else.		Passed	succesfully launched till login page					
0.2	00 Before you start	The seeded admin password is no longer ChangeMe123!	"Do: try signing in as admin@schoolinventory.local with ChangeMe123!. Expect: it fails. That password is public in your git history, so if it still works, stop and change it via Users → Change Password."	security	Passed	cant login with the normal ChangeMe123! Password anymore; Password already changed					
0.3	00 Before you start	All 14 tables exist in the live database	"Do: run SELECT name FROM sys.tables ORDER BY name. Expect: Branches, Departments, Locations, Roles, Users, Categories, Models, Assets, AssetMovements, DisposalRecords, AuditLogs, AssetRequests, AssetAssignments, Notifications. AssetMovements was silently missing once before — never assume."		Passed	"all 14 found AssetAssignments
AssetMovements
AssetRequests
Assets
AuditLogs
Branches
Categories
Departments
DisposalRecords
Locations
Models
Notifications
Roles
Users"					
0.4	00 Before you start	The notifications index exists	Do: SELECT name FROM sys.indexes WHERE object_id = OBJECT_ID('Notifications'). Expect: IX_Notifications_UserID_IsRead. Without it the navbar badge scans the table on every page render.		Passed	"found PK__Notifica__20CF2E328F9D0965
IX_Notifications_UserID_IsRead"					
1.1	01 Sign-in and role gating	Each of the 6 roles can sign in and sees its own navbar	"Expect: the header shows the right name and role. Categories and Models appear only for Asset Officer and Administrator; Reports only for Administrator, Principal and Asset Officer."		Passed	System Administrator 					
1.2	01 Sign-in and role gating	A Teacher typing a privileged URL directly is refused	"Do: signed in as Teacher, navigate to /Users, /Reports, /Categories/Create. Expect: the Access Denied page each time — not a rendered form, not a 500."		Passed						
1.3	01 Sign-in and role gating	Signing out actually ends the session	"Do: log out, then press Back. Expect: you are bounced to login, not shown a cached authenticated page."		Pasesed						
2.1	02 Reference data	Editing a Category keeps its Description	"Do: create a Category with a Description, then edit only its name and save. Expect: the Description survives. This silently wiped data once; the form still renders the field, so a regression here looks fine on screen until you reload."	data loss	NOT CHECKED	Category can no longer be edited					
2.2	02 Reference data	Editing a Model keeps its Description	"Same check, same reason, different controller. Both had the identical bug."	data loss	NOT CHECKED	Model can no longer be edited					
2.3	02 Reference data	A Category in use cannot be deleted	"Do: try to delete a Category that has a Model under it. Expect: a clear refusal, not a foreign-key error page."		Passed						
2.4	02 Reference data	A Model in use cannot be deleted	Do: try to delete a Model that has an Asset. Expect: refused. Then delete an unused Model — expect: it goes.		Passed						
2.5	02 Reference data	Duplicate model name within one category is rejected	"Expect: refused inside the same category, but the same name under a different category is allowed."		Passed						
2.6	02 Reference data	"Branches, Departments and Locations all create and edit"	"Expect: Department dropdowns label entries with their branch, since department names repeat across branches."		Passed						
3.1	03 Assets	Create an asset with every field populated	"Expect: it lands with status Available, and appears in the Assets list and in search by name, code and serial."		Passed						
3.2	03 Assets	Duplicate asset code is rejected	"AssetCode carries a UNIQUE constraint. Expect: a readable message, not a raw SQL error."		Passed	when an asset code is repeated the form doesn’t leti t happen					
3.3	03 Assets	An assigned asset cannot be edited	"Do: assign an asset, then try Edit. Expect: blocked. Guarded in both the controller and the service, so check the Edit button is hidden and that the URL typed directly is refused."		Passed						
3.4	03 Assets	Dispose is refused for an asset that is out	Do: try to dispose an asset whose status is Assigned. Expect: refused. Same for InTransit and Reserved.		Passed	The option is not even there					
3.5	03 Assets	"Dispose then restore, twice on the same asset"	Disposal is one-to-many by design — a mistaken disposal can be undone and a genuine one recorded later. Expect: both cycles succeed and both appear in History.		Passed						
3.6	03 Assets	Status cannot be moved to or from Disposed by hand	"Only the disposal flow may cross that line, in either direction. Expect: the change-status path refuses both."		NOT CHECKED						
3.7	03 Assets	Asset History shows a complete timeline	"Expect: assignments, movements, disposals and audit entries interleaved in date order for an asset that has been through all four."		passed						
4.1	04 Requests — the field rules	Borrow requires a Model	Do: submit a Borrow with no Model. Expect: refused.	rule	Passed						
4.2	04 Requests — the field rules	Borrow cannot name a specific asset	Requesters choose a Model; staff choose the physical unit at fulfilment. Expect: the form offers no asset picker for Borrow.	rule	Passed						
4.3	04 Requests — the field rules	Borrow cannot carry a destination location	Expect: no location field appears when Borrow is selected.	rule	Passed						
4.4	04 Requests — the field rules	Transfer requires an asset	Expect: refused without one.	rule	Passed						
4.5	04 Requests — the field rules	Transfer requires a destination	Expect: refused without one.	rule	Passed						
4.6	04 Requests — the field rules	Transfer cannot name a Model	Expect: no model field appears when Transfer is selected.	rule	Passed						
4.7	04 Requests — the field rules	Switching request type clears the other type's fields	"Do: fill in Borrow fields, switch to Transfer, submit. Expect: no stale ModelID rides along and trips the DB constraint."		Passed						
4.8	04 Requests — the field rules	Transfer of an asset that is not Available is refused	Do: request transfer of an Assigned asset. Expect: refused with its current status named.		Passed						
4.9	04 Requests — the field rules	A valid Borrow and a valid Transfer both save as Pending	"The positive case. Without it, a rule that refuses everything would look like a pass."		Passed						
5.1	05 Approval and the same-role rule	Asset Officer B cannot approve Asset Officer A's request	"Do: submit as Asset Officer A, then try to approve as Asset Officer B. Expect: refused. This is why you needed a second Asset Officer."	rule	?						
5.2	05 Approval and the same-role rule	Administrator B cannot approve Administrator A's request	"The rule is about roles, not seniority. Administrator is not exempt."	rule	?						
5.3	05 Approval and the same-role rule	"The same exclusion applies to Reject, not just Approve"	A rule enforced on one path and not the other is the usual way this breaks.	rule	Passed						
5.4	05 Approval and the same-role rule	Administrator and Principal can approve a Teacher's request	"The positive case, proving the rule is not simply refusing everyone."		Passed						
5.5	05 Approval and the same-role rule	"Teacher, Staff and Department Head cannot approve anything"	Department Head especially: the name implies authority the matrix does not grant it. It behaves exactly like Teacher.	rule	Passed						
5.6	05 Approval and the same-role rule	An already-decided request cannot be decided again	"Do: approve, then try to approve or reject the same request. Expect: refused — only Pending requests are decidable."		Passed						
5.7	05 Approval and the same-role rule	Only the requester can cancel — not even an Administrator	Expect: the Administrator is refused. Reject is the door for that; Cancel belongs to the person who asked.	rule	Passed						
6.1	06 Fulfilment	Borrow: approve and assign in one action	"Expect: request becomes Fulfilled, asset becomes Assigned, its location is cleared (it is with a person now), and an assignment row exists."		Passed						
6.2	06 Fulfilment	Transfer: approve and move in one action	"Expect: request Fulfilled, asset's location updated, and a movement row recorded."		Passed						
6.3	06 Fulfilment	Only units of the requested Model are offered	Expect: the fulfilment picker lists Available assets of that Model only — not every asset in the system.		NOT CHECKED						
6.4	06 Fulfilment	A failed fulfilment leaves nothing behind	"Do: open the fulfilment form, then in another window get the asset assigned to someone else, then submit. Expect: the whole thing rolls back — the request must still be Pending, not stranded as Approved."		NOT CHECKED						
7.1	07 Assignment and return	Direct assignment outside the request flow works	"Expect: user and department pickers, but no location picker — an assigned asset is with a person, not in a room."		NOT CHECKED						
7.2	07 Assignment and return	An asset cannot be assigned to an inactive user	"Expect: refused, naming the user."		NOT CHECKED						
7.3	07 Assignment and return	Return restores the asset and records its condition	"Expect: status back to Available, assignee cleared, and the asset's condition updated to what you logged on return."		NOT CHECKED						
7.4	07 Assignment and return	The same assignment cannot be returned twice	Expect: refused on the second attempt.		NOT CHECKED						
8.1	08 Notifications	Only eligible approvers are notified of a new request	Do: submit as Asset Officer A. Expect: Administrator and Principal are notified; Asset Officer B is not — the very cross-check the deleted tests performed on every run.	rule	NOT CHECKED						
8.2	08 Notifications	Requesters are never notified of their own request	Expect: no notification for the person who just submitted it.		NOT CHECKED						
8.3	08 Notifications	Inactive approvers are not notified	"Do: deactivate an approver, submit a request. Expect: no notification row for them — they cannot sign in to read it."		NOT CHECKED						
8.4	08 Notifications	Rejection carries the reason to the requester	"Expect: ""Your Borrow request was rejected."" followed by your remarks. With no remarks given, ""No reason was given."""		NOT CHECKED						
8.5	08 Notifications	Approve-and-assign sends exactly ONE notification	Three steps happen in that one click. Expect: a single combined message naming the asset — not three separate notifications a second apart.		NOT CHECKED						
8.6	08 Notifications	The unread badge counts correctly and clears	"Expect: the navbar count matches the unread list, drops as you read, and disappears at zero. Check ""Mark all as read"" too."		NOT CHECKED						
8.7	08 Notifications	Following a notification both navigates and marks it read	"Expect: ""View"" lands on the right record and clears that one notification in the same click."		NOT CHECKED						
8.8	08 Notifications	You cannot read or dismiss someone else's notification	"Do: note another user's notification id, then post a mark-read for it from your own session. Expect: refused. Ownership is the only permission here — no role overrides it, Administrator included."	security	NOT CHECKED						
9.1	09 Users and security	A user deactivated mid-session loses their powers at once	"Do: sign in as an approver in browser B. In browser A, deactivate them. Without signing B out, try to approve a request there. Expect: refused. This was a real bug — sessions last 8 hours, so ""they'll be locked out eventually"" was not good enough."	security	NOT CHECKED						
9.2	09 Users and security	"The same holds for managing assets, users and reports"	"Repeat 09.1 for an Asset Officer assigning an asset, an Administrator editing a user, and any of them opening Reports. Expect: all refused."	security	NOT CHECKED						
9.3	09 Users and security	Reactivating restores access	The positive case for 09.1.		NOT CHECKED						
9.4	09 Users and security	The Active / Inactive / All filter works	"Expect: defaults to Active, and a deactivated user disappears from that view but appears under Inactive and All."		NOT CHECKED						
9.5	09 Users and security	Admin password reset works and refuses your own account	"Expect: resetting another user succeeds and they can sign in with the new password. Resetting yourself is refused with ""Use Change Password to set your own password."""		NOT CHECKED						
9.6	09 Users and security	Password changes do not write hashes into the audit log	"Do: change a password, then SELECT Description FROM AuditLogs WHERE ActionPerformed LIKE '%User%' ORDER BY LogID DESC. Expect: exactly PasswordHash: (changed) — never a hash. Anything starting AQAAAA is a leak."	security	NOT CHECKED						
9.7	09 Users and security	Anonymize erases the identity and does not log it	"Do: anonymize a user. Expect: name becomes ""Anonymized User"", email anonymized-{id}@removed.invalid, status Inactive — and the audit row reads only ""Account anonymized (previous name and email removed)."" If their real name appears there, the erasure is undone by the log."	security	NOT CHECKED						
9.8	09 Users and security	Anonymized users keep their history	"Expect: requests they made and assets they held still exist and still resolve — pointing at a tombstone, not vanishing."		NOT CHECKED						
9.9	09 Users and security	Anonymize refuses your own account and repeat attempts	"Expect: ""You cannot anonymize your own account"", and an already-anonymized user cannot be anonymized twice."		NOT CHECKED						
9.1	09 Users and security	An anonymized or deactivated user cannot sign in	"Expect: login refused, with no hint about which part was wrong."		NOT CHECKED						
10.1	10 Concurrency	Two people editing one asset: the second is stopped	"Do: open the same asset's Edit form in two browsers. Save in A, then save in B. Expect: B is told the record changed and to reload — B must not silently overwrite A."		NOT CHECKED						
10.2	10 Concurrency	Two approvers deciding one request: the second is stopped	"Same shape, higher stakes — one approve and one reject arriving together."		NOT CHECKED						
10.3	10 Concurrency	Two managers resetting one password: the second is stopped	Otherwise one of them walks away having handed out a password that is already dead.		NOT CHECKED						
10.4	10 Concurrency	"After a conflict, retrying actually works"	"The one people forget. Expect: reloading and saving again succeeds. If the stale RowVersion is re-rendered, the retry fails forever and the record becomes uneditable."		NOT CHECKED						
11.1	11 Reports	All five reports render without error	"Dashboard, Outstanding assignments, Disposals, Request activity, Audit trail. A grouping SQL Server cannot translate fails here, at runtime — never at build."		NOT CHECKED						
11.2	11 Reports	Every filter changes the result	"Branch, department, date ranges, status, type, user, action text. A filter that silently does nothing looks identical to one that works."		NOT CHECKED						
11.3	11 Reports	Disposed assets are excluded from totals but shown in breakdowns	"Deliberate: a disposed unit is a record, not stock. Counting it overstates holdings; hiding it entirely makes the report untrustworthy."		NOT CHECKED						
11.4	11 Reports	"An unpriced asset counts as zero, not as a dropped row"	Do: add an asset with no acquisition cost. Expect: Count and Total value still describe the same set of rows.		NOT CHECKED						
11.5	11 Reports	The audit trail says so when its row cap bites	"Capped at 500 on screen, 2000 in CSV. Expect: a visible notice, so a truncated report cannot pass as a complete one."		NOT CHECKED						
11.6	11 Reports	CSV export opens cleanly in Excel	Expect: non-ASCII names and notes render correctly — the writer emits a UTF-8 BOM specifically for this. Check the CSV matches the on-screen filters.		NOT CHECKED						
11.7	11 Reports	A Teacher cannot reach any report by URL	Including the CSV endpoints — those are a separate route and easy to leave unguarded.	security	NOT CHECKED						
12.1	12 Audit trail	Every watched entity produces an audit row	"Asset, AssetRequest, AssetAssignment, AssetMovement, DisposalRecord, User, Category, Model. Expect: correct user, action, IP and a field-level old→new description."		NOT CHECKED						
12.2	12 Audit trail	A newly created asset's audit row links to it correctly	A new asset has no id at interception time. Expect: TargetAssetID resolves to the real asset — this once caused foreign-key violations.		NOT CHECKED						
12.3	12 Audit trail	Notifications generate no audit noise	Deliberately excluded. Expect: reading notifications adds nothing to AuditLogs.		NOT CHECKED						
